Guide to the Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation Pittsburgh Works Records, 1918-1970 AIS.1988.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation Pittsburgh Works Records
1918-1970
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation. Pittsburgh Works
AIS.1988.07
104 Linear Feet (82 boxes and 57 reels of microfilm)
The Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation's mill in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, began producing steel in 1886 and had facilities on both banks of the Monongahela River. This collection includes personnel cards for employees of Jones & Laughlin's plant in south side Pittsburgh.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection includes personnel cards for employees of Jones & Laughlin's plant in south side Pittsburgh. These cards include the worker's name, date and place of birth, nationality, race, and wage rate. Payroll information for several departments within the works is also present.
Previous Citation
Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation, Pittsburgh Works Records, 1918-1970, AIS.1988.07, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
Personnel cards (Reels 15-57 and Boxes 1-77, 80-82) are closed for 50 years after their date of creation. Access to this collection requires a signed confidentiality agreement. Please contact the Archives Service Center for more information.
Acquisition Information
Gift of LTV Asset Control Group in 1988 and Pittsburgh History & Landmarks Foundation in 1993.
History
The American Iron Works was founded by John and Bernard Lauth in 1853. Benjamin F. Jones bought into the works and James Laughlin joined his rolling mill with the company to form the Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation. The mill in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, had facilities on both banks of the Monongahela River. The Eliza blast furnaces in Hazelwood were connected to the rest of the mill on the south side by a bridge that transported railcars filled with hot pig iron. In 1974, Ling-Temco-Vought purchased Jones & Laughlin Corporation as part of LTV Steel and all production facilities were closed in 1989.
Related Material
Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation, Pittsburgh Works Earning Records, 1862-1901, AIS.1974.23, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh
Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation Historical Records, 1871-1953, AIS.1973.07, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh
Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation Records, 1902-1959, AIS.1978.09, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh
Labor; Business and Industry; Steel industry and trade -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Payroll records; Iron and steel workers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation. Pittsburgh Works
- Transfer Payroll, Bee-Hive Coke Ovens, 1919-1926 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 4, Reel 1-4)
- Transfer Payroll, Eliza Works, 1919-1926 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 4, Reel 5-8)
- Transfer Payroll, Furnace Fronts, 1926 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 4, Reel 9)
- Byproduct Coke Oven, 1926 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 4, Reel 10)
- Multidepartmental, November-December 1930 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 4, Reel 11-12)
- No. 11 Mill, 1918-1924 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 4, Reel 13-14)
- Rate Cards [RESTRICTED], 1919-1970 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 4, Reel 15-57)
- Rate Cards [RESTRICTED], 1919-1970 (Box 1-77)
- Manuals and Notebooks (Box 78)
- Mill Blueprints and Questionnaires (Box 79)
- Termination Notices and Rate Cards [RESTRICTED] (Box 80)
- Pay Cards [RESTRICTED], 1919 (Box 81)
- Rate Cards [RESTRICTED] (Box 82)